MELINDA CHEN

Hagen Blvd,. El Cerrito, CA 94530 (425) 615-3232 melindachen0517@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Highly motivated marketing professional with over three years of international experience, broad background in global marketing, brand development, and commitment to corporate objectives. Skilled at creating promotional materials, competitive analysis and acting as liaison with partners, suppliers and clients. Successful in increasing ROI in advertising by optimizing promotional strategy.

- Team Building
- Social Media Promotion
- Global Perspective Analysis
- Strong Oral and Written Communication
- Advanced English and Native Chinese
- Qualitative Marketing Research
- Strategic Leadership
- Operational Management
- Business Development
- Creative Entrepreneurship

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SagaCity Media, Inc. (Seattle Met Bride & Groom Magazine), Seattle, WA

Marketing/Advertising Intern

January, 2014 – June, 2014

- Managed and improved advertising databases.
- Analyzed and assessed top competitors' bridal fashion ad and popular content.
- Developed and strengthened public relations by working closely with business partners.
- Promoted a new marketing plan that brought to more website hits.
- Proposed efficient marketing strategy increasing ROI by at least 200%.

Metro Seattle Real Estate Experts Group-Re/Max, Seattle, WA

Global Marketing Specialist Intern

July, 2013 – October, 2013

- Built and managed marketing plans, positioned products, and created collateral content.
- Extended brand to international level by identifying requirements for marketing strategy.
- Conducted market research and created new branding ideas to ensure effective strategy and direction.
- Maintained public website and updated latest marketing information via different social media platforms.

City University of Seattle, Enactus, Seattle, WA

Marketing Chair & Social Media Chair

June, 2012 – June, 2014

- Designed Annual Report, Team Profile, and Business Card for team projects in regional competition, which contributed to winning U.S national competition in 2013 and 2014.
- Organized teams for projects around community events (e.g. Giving Garden, Thanksgiving Festival, The Seattle Blind Cafe, Earth Day, and Open House for CityU).
- Created all event flyers and taken active role in volunteering for Enactus events, projects, and leadership roles.
- Extended Enactus branding that result in 100% increase in weekly meeting participation and 95% increase in facebook following.

Kuebler Automation Trading Co, Ltd. (Germany Company), Shanghai, China

Materials Sourcing Assistant

July, 2011 – March, 2012

- Purchased products and handled emergency situations.
- Acted as liaison with customers, suppliers, and co-workers inside and outside the company.
- Gathered and analyzed data, developed rationale for decisions.
- Considered alternatives and assessed the impact and potential problems.

Dan-Marine (Far East), Ltd. (Canada & Hong Kong Joint Venture Company), Shanghai, China

Project Assistant & Marketing Executive

July, 2010 – July, 2011

- Assisted sales manager doing project documentary work.
- Coordinated team to win the championship and received high acclaim from our management in the competition of "Group Annual Performance".
- Promoted to participate in marketing specialist training, and worked with all sales managers in mainland China region to update the Hot List promptly.
- Preformed report from Enterprise Resource Planning system (ERP system) and emailed to all of our European suppliers and to corporate headquarters once a month.

Tai Kang life Insurance (State-owned Enterprise), Shanghai, China

Administration Executive/Assistant (Internship)

September, 2009 – December, 2009

- Assisted the HR manager in employment recruitment, reviewed resumes, chose candidates for manager's review.
- Conducted initial candidate interviews.
- Formulated training plans and organized their implementation.

AWARDS

CityU Dean's List 2012~2014 June, 2013; October, 2013; February, 2014

June, 2014

CityU Merit-Based Scholarship April, 2013; October, 2013

Enactus Platinum Service Leadership Award 2013/2014 January, 2014

CityU Enactus Leadership Scholarship October, 2012; January, 2013; April, 2013; October, 2013; January, 2014; April, 2014

EDUCATION

City University of Seattle, WA

March, 2012 — June, 2014

Masters of Business in Administration, Global Marketing Management

Courses: Applied Marketing; Strategic Brand Creation & Management;

Channel Management; Public Relations and Media Management;

Consumer Behavior

Shanghai International Studies University, Shanghai

September, 2007 – June, 2011

Bachelor's Degree, English language